hello my name is green and welcome back
to another episode of hermit craft as
you can see behind me there is only two
days left until this happens obviously
this is already launched in the air so
what are we counting down to well we'll
find out by the end of this episode it's
going to be magnificent what do you
think Ren not saying much today are we
Ren so let's crack on with today's
episode we've got a lot to do
hi Ren I've been collecting lots of
things over here I've been trying to
gather all the materials I need for the
big reveal the big prank the big thing
that's happening and I came across this
for hippies top secret let's take a look
play me the far music disc and a map
take a look at the map unspeakable
things reactor hangar ok so I have a
jukebox somewhere I'm gonna play this
there we go got one right let's play
this and see what happens
dear hippies you don't know me I don't
know you well that's kind of it that way
please cab has information for sale
information on a mysterious area 77
don't believe me in addition to this
record disc there is a map inside this
barrel this map may have information
about a certain object that went missing
from your hippocampus the reactive
access how do I know this well I know
everything like out that cop
deep investigation I have obtained
secret recordings of agents inside area
77 recordings which reveal a top-secret
location is known only as s4 if you wish
to obtain these recordings leave a small
fortune of diamonds in this barrel
within 24 hours for mayor I will deliver
the recordings and the secret tapes of
area 77 shall be yours
okay so cub knows not to stop in five
seconds selfish how
just kidding I always wonder he got well
played cubby you got me okay so from I
might need to listen to that again but
from what I can tell cub he thinks he's
being sliced like made his voice a
little deeper but you could totally tell
that its cub okay so it seems like cub
he's put on that you remember when we
saw kerb last episode and he had like
glasses on her stuff he's been
infiltrating area 77 and he's got a
bunch of information that he's trying to
sell to us he said a small fortune I
don't really wanna I don't really want
to give him loads of diamonds but I do
need that information I do need to know
exactly where it is the problem that
we've got at the moment is that we've
got all of these tunnels underneath that
go to various places we have no idea
where the time machine is however I
actually saw in my comments a bunch of
people telling me to go back to my
original base and I don't even mean my
big base I mean the pineapple under the
sea let's go back to my old base because
there are some comments that have been
telling me to do something and there's
too many of them for it to just be
nonsense
maybe Cubs information is really just
this and all of you guys have just got
exactly the same information for me
something along those lines I don't know
wow it's been a long time since we've
been here so the comments said that it's
under the pineapple now that's where cub
is saying that it is then well we're
just gonna find out aren't we maybe this
is where Cubs information leads anyway
and therefore I don't have to pay him
I'm gonna do anything I can not to pay
cub if I can't help you so it said go
into the pineapple and then this is this
is so oh this is from like over a year
ago this is the beginning of the season
it said to flick the lever on Geary now
this is Gary oh okay maybe maybe this
information look at that register
maybe this information does mean
something oh the power of time travel is
too powerful for anyone to have permits
in black investigation
so they
Time Machine right under my nose how
long has it literally been here from the
start to be honest I would have that's
such a good hiding place I never would
have come back here and looked for the
time machine I wouldn't have why would I
ever come back here it's no longer there
meaning they've since moved it okay so
it wasn't there I really don't want to
have to pay KUB so maybe we can go and
investigate area 77 ourselves and see if
we can find it if kerb is able to just
walk around area 77 maybe we can also
find a way in
I'm guessing that the time machine was
there for a really long time but now
they've actually moved it into the vault
and we need to find out where this vault
is so I've had another idea
remember last episode when we saw this
thing the area 77 tall well what if I
team up with Wren and see if we can get
a tour of this place of area 77 and see
if we can just find the time machine let
me see if I can find Wren and see if
he's up for the task rent I got to show
you come here yes I don't know if you've
seen this but someone who wants to be
anonymous
aka Cub fan 1:35 left us right no in
here it's a music disc and a map and
basically he said can you give me loads
of diamonds and I will tell you where
the time machine is that's basically I
don't want to give him lots of diamonds
but I did see her over in false well
that falsey is dishing out some tours of
actual area 77 so right thinking instead
of giving kerb loads of diamonds we
could go on the tour and see if we can
just find your reactor in my time
machine by ourselves and save ourselves
a bit of the blue stuff you know that
does sound like a plan I mean is okay we
just wander in there you know oh yeah
because I've created some masterpieces
I've got us a couple of disguises so
that they won't they won't know who hmm
as Taylor green been added again
you Betty ass agree on what the heck is
this let me take my armor let me take my
mouth we're touristy tourists miss
Hearst Oh got the Hawaiian shirts going
on yeah white socks okay so the camera
you got the suspenders what's on my face
though dude it's like what you think
mustache and it's like the glasses with
the big fake nose and the mustache and
everything this might be crazy enough to
work I mean like are we going in as
ourselves because that might just not
make much sense we should be like other
people or something maybe my accents
aren't very good so I could I don't
think I can do that very convincingly I
can do I can do like a proper upper
class British person like oh hello
Rittenhouse how's it going you know yeah
oh hello Alfred LF you want to be Alfred
oh yeah I'll be Alfred I'll be Alf
Alfred Greene's worth Alfred Greene oh I
like it and it was your name I shall be
Nigel Wren feather
Nigel rain feather we're here for a tour
dude this is gonna work Fosse can we get
one of those area 77 tools if you're
free I don't know how we're gonna sell
this one yeah I mean I think we just
have to run with it and hope it works
okay she's there Alfred Tally Ho oh
she's right here okay hello let's join
her hello hello madam hello false
symmetry
how you doing s it's a fetching name I
must say Alfred very fetching indeed
good what are you guys dressed up for
like what I am alpha greens Werth and we
and this is my my Chum hello Nigel Nigel
red feather we're here for the tour yes
we've heard that it's smashing okay well
tours for 25 diamonds each
Yeah right away that's just a little bit
steep I must say Alfred happy I was
hoping to get to scale in it later this
afternoon
right oh yes oh that is very very cheap
yes I left my wallet at home
Nigel oh right that's okay I've got you
I've got you a gentleman sir but farm
anyway those came from right are we
ready - yes
yeah follow me guys we're going straight
through the entrance here we are Nigel
at the area 77 very excited yes is this
the world right come on guys okay right
okay three here three here that we can't
we can't get through that side so this
is some magnificent a few tests I must
say I'm quite impressed Oh what have you
done L frigid there's a button there was
a button my my fellow oh right I see
bring your camera
oh yes did you bring your camera
apparatus we need to take some pictures
of this I think it's like Oh Alfred I
say you've brought up just a bit of
jousting Oh fantastic shot Nigel Nigel
this way yes sorry yes Korean press f2 a
lot we need screen shots
I mean Alfred I hope you're taking some
fabulous pictures I am I'm taking plenty
I say on this thing it's is there
perhaps a good look at a small white box
and a small green glass object we can we
can try and find that I I don't know
well that is exactly but Alfred I'm not
so sure of the competency of this
particular tour guide
my diamonds okay so uh straight had this
there's a hanger
well a few hangers but this one on the
left is particularly interesting do
that's that's there that's bread Bob's
nuclear reactor I need that I need that
back can you show me this this
delightful hangar over here we'll see
yes I wouldn't go there run that's
that's it's not sorry
wise up friend okay oh yes Alfred I must
say I've quite enjoyed this to us so far
it's been spectacular
smell you later
doc in 77 worst talk I've ever that is
the end of the tour can I be a Nigel
Rainsford forever that was fun
freakin hippies you know I think after
after we're done being hippies renwick
we've just got to become British
gentlemen that's that's our next yes
that's our next thing we're gonna make a
big castle and we're gonna ride forces
and all that sort of stuff that sounds
beautiful that was really successful
though look at this it's the nuclear
reactor my tank but I didn't get my job
didn't get anywhere near my time machine
of course doc has to log in the second
we get anywhere close of course I got
some I got some good screenshots though
yeah that many good ones yeah
but my camera was snapping away by dude
I think we've got some good info out of
this nice you gotta hide that thing
they're just gonna come and get that
snack that straight back you know
they're gonna stash yeah that's good
that's a good thing I'm gonna hide it in
a shroom man nobody nobody suspects of
giant shroom right
maybe that's a terrible hiding place
that's it all things considered I don't
think that went too badly we got the
reactor back but that was the stupidest
thing I think we've ever done
I don't think false thought we were
actually British tourists at all but it
was nice of her to play along anyway
having said that we didn't get any
closer to the actual time machine so I'm
just gonna say forget it right I've put
the 50 diamonds in I've paid I've paid
for it I don't know what a small fortune
is but that's that's a pretty that's a
decent amount of diamonds so I need the
information I need to know where it is
because I don't I don't really want to
have to go through that again I need to
know exactly where the time machine is
on here because I could spend hours and
hours tunneling under each and
everything or I could know exactly where
it is so if I get that information then
we can get the time machine very very
easily but there's only two days left
two days left so I actually need to work
on the next part of this because well
I've only got a few days to do it so
let's do a quick time-lapse of us
preparing the RV for operation flower
power so what I'm going to be building
is a slime block redstone machine but I
didn't design it it's very important
that you understand this this is an
incredibly complicated piece of
machinery and I had to use someone
else's design methods actually put this
together for me and made a tutorial on
how to make this exact slime block
redstone machine so if you want to see
that there is a link to it in the
description if you were to check it out
after the episode but just take a look
at it this I had no idea what I was
building but thankfully methods put this
together for me so a big shout out to
him and hopefully it will then launch
from the big RV over into area 77 and
you'll see why so I finished the RV it
is a pretty cool slime block machine but
it looked a little bit strange coming
out of the belly of the RV so now I
decided to add a little
face now how it looks like some sort of
angry Mario karts dial machine and I
think it works quite well but everything
is set up indeed and there's only one
day left it won't be long now until it's
time to launch that is all set up the
angry eyes are there when this launches
it all goes down and I also went over
here for the hippie top secret thing and
there is some s4 info so let's have a
quick lesson and see if cub has any
information that will help us well well
well maybe you lad aren't so bad after
all
s4 aka sector for its so-called
Forbidden Zone yep as for the location
of this s4 I'll leave it to Captain
angry eyes himself to explain site is
prep duck we just need to bring in the
package s4 no it's down behind we
believe that these bond payment chambers
are referring to sector two we're
playing some beings of all sort are kept
you'll know when you see him walk past
sector two and you'll come to an airlock
you'll need to use your knowledge of
music to get past them drop down the
chute and you're in the machine you seek
is currently hooked nope I know exactly
where it is cub actually went and
recorded Skaar giving away the location
somehow I don't even know if Skaar knows
about that okay well thank you cub there
that's brilliant so we now know if we
head down into the bowels of the system
I can point out on a map exactly where
this is and this also means that our
tunnel is actually already heading in
the right direction ok so you see on
this map we have these this area here
now this isn't updated but there's loads
of hangars here but there's also this
big one here from what I can tell this
is where they store all of their stuff
and I think this is what skull was
talking about he was saying that they
weren't putting it there that they've
moved it to here
and I can tell you that our tunnel runs
all the way here to here and it goes
down left and it is actually just about
there
Wow okay so I just need to finish off
this tunnel because that's just I just
got a little bit further to go until I
can hit this area right here so I
haven't got a lot of time to be digging
so instead of digging I'm gonna speed up
the process and grab some of my TNT
fortunately I keep fortunately I keep a
tiny amount of TNT on me at all times
let's take this down into the tunnel and
make it that little bit longer because
like I said we've only got less than 24
hours until the the big distraction
happens and when that goes down that's
when we need to make a break for it in
the tunnel down we go see how long this
tunnel has gotten it's getting a bit out
of hand really so I got this far but I
actually need to go all the way along
here and turn right so this is pretty
much as far as I've got so far so if I
just take the blocks that I need what
we're gonna do is set this thing up to
glow so that we don't have any issues
getting there in time because it
actually takes a really long time to
mine anything like this I don't know why
I didn't do this from the get-go this
would have been really clever okay here
we go three two one doc and scar aren't
online so I can get away with this
ow we're making our way oh this is so
much faster I can't believe I didn't do
this absolutely perfect nice
well that saved me a whole bunch of time
Oh scared me
no now according to my map we should be
pretty much directly under the hangar so
I don't really want to go too much
further because the second we break in
they're gonna know that we're here and
they're gonna move the time machine this
is how it's gonna go down we're gonna
set off the distraction then we're gonna
hop down into the tunnels break in get
the time machine
get out win the game whatever game there
is that's pretty much the job done we
just need to decorate this to make this
the proper tunnel and then we will be
all red cheese I didn't I only just got
out of here I only just created this
place and it's a mob farm already now
that job is done we need to just kill a
tiny bit of time and I'll tell you what
needs doing
suhara again it needs desperately to be
restocked it's being well we're actually
selling a lot of things and we can't
keep up so I'm gonna have to spend a
little bit of time just stocking up a
little bit so we have to spend a little
bit of time giving that some attention a
scale is actually online restocking
Sahara and I need to provide the sand
for the system but at first I thought
I'd restock Sahara eats since I'm here
and I've collected a bunch of golden
carats to do it so I'm gonna go straight
over to a desert and I'm gonna pick up
as many shulker boxes as I can be
bothered to mine so let's go
speaking of Sahara its had a pretty big
upgrade that's going on and over here
where my current farm used to be there's
now a mini trading Hall all with all
green
in scales and mumbos and fake fish great
noise so what you do is you grab some
emeralds from the emerald output take
them over to the villages and trade to
your heart's content this is a much
faster way of getting golden carats than
the way I was doing it growing them
manually you just trade them with these
guys and wait for them to restock and
then you've got infinite golden carats
so I've got a couple of stacks there
immediately very very simply but I've
also got to deliver all of the shoka
boxes full of sand to iskele who is
doing something up there so whoever is
getting more and more complicated
everyday areas see if I can get his
attention there we go right what have we
got here for you today we have got sand
sand sand sand sand sand sand sand sand
Mambo actually managed to sell these
Thank You doc and mumbo only mumbo sold
a membership to himself unbelievable
yeah I was gonna take pity on you mumbo
I was gonna buy one from you but you've
just gone and been rather cheeky wait
Sahara can stock now that's awesome so
how is such an incredible work of
Minecraft engineering so over here at
the deal section most of the deals that
I created in fact all of the deals have
now been sold and all of the diamonds
have been put away next episode I'm
definitely gonna have to stock this up
again with some fresh boxes but I can't
make them faster than they disappear
it's impossible to keep up with it
sounds like a song
you can you could definitely make a song
out of this beat I actually have one box
that I can put in right now I just need
to rename it it's a box full of dyes and
it's just yeah it's basically just got a
lot of useful dyes very cheap from my
flower farm so the first thing I'm going
to do is just call this a did you dye
for diamonds for all of those dyes dyes
are one of those things that you usually
need but never have any lying around so
I'm gonna pop that straight into the
system and leave it there there we go
did you die and I'm actually going to
create lots of did you dye boxes as soon
as I get my time machine back I will
then be able to create as many of these
as possible full of blue light gray
orange yellow red purple pink all of the
good stuff and then and hopefully that
will help keep Sahara a bit more stocked
as well oh by the way this is Sarah our
Sahara Cat super cute so what we do is
we just simply walk through all of these
trade with them as much as possible
because we basically have free emeralds
we can get everything that we need so
quartz terracotta we just make our way
through and we stock up on this sort of
thing we can sell all this at Sahara
because we basically just have unlimited
amounts of it it's a little bit
time-consuming sometimes having to go
through every single villager but on the
whole works pretty well I've been
stocking up on some terra cotta over
here this can be a Sahara nail box when
that's all finished and then there's one
here for some courts this can be either
a Sahara now all we can put it in the
system itself and of course we can stock
up on the golden carats which are a big
big seller but I think that's enough of
Sahara we've done a little bit of
restocking this cow only told me to get
my hands on some sand which I've now
done he seems to have stocked up on
everything else it's making its way
through I I'll be honest with you I
don't really know how all of this works
so I'm kind of just a a goblin a sand
goblin I have to go and collect all of
this stuff and just give it to his scale
to put inside of the machine
when it's done this thing will be full
anyway all we got to do now is head back
to the hippie land where it will soon be
time to seize the time machine from area
77 but I'm gonna need the help of Red
Dog and impulse for this one
hippies it is a launch day mark - I
don't know if you've seen but I've
created a mini RV poking out of the
belly of the giant RV it's very urban if
I'm going to be completely honest with
you gene it's very weird it's hideous
anyway so reason you're here is I
actually need your help so the RV coming
out of the RV is that's really weird RVs
is leaving the other RV you actually
need your help because that's only one
part of it I need to cover area 77 in
bonemeal in flowers as a flower power
prank but you've seen how big this area
is
I need a young man power to make this
happen so are you guys are you guys
ready to help me out with this one oh
yeah flower bleep ugly bro we got you
sweet okay and then this should give us
sufficient distraction to then go down
into the tunnel system make our way to
the time machine and get it the heck out
of there 50-50 chance I haven't tested
it because the problem with this is it's
a very complicated redstone machine and
you can't really test it because if you
test it it leaves the building
so right I give it a 50/50 impulse would
you be able to set the timer back to a
nine second countdown yep let's do it
I'll get over there instead of right now
every time I'm ready for the countdown
good luck boys okay the longer that we
get the closer we get to launch the more
convinced I am is like 90 percent
failure rate just launch the countdown I
can't I can't bear okay here we go hated
machine I don't know if it's
to work here gonna like eight seven six
five four three two and lag no is it
movie then this is lag I will move it a
little bit exact hundred percent favor
right I don't even know where to begin
man I'm sorry about that
it's a I've rebates it again yeah I
don't really understand how this thing
works so I don't know what I did wrong
and I also don't know if I did it right
this time
so seven I'm gonna I'm gonna give it
70/30 on a fail so right let's go let's
go for it you ready okay okay yeah it's
going and we're at six six beautiful
sight it was this is how you've got to
travel now and Bob Brenly this is how
red bulbs actually gonna fly around
right wow this is gonna be a slow going
but yeah that is epic look at it go
plant some flowers now right yeah yeah
we need to get to okay I've got some
invisibility potions for everyone so
that if dr. pecks car logon we are all
good so invisibility potion up each
thank you beautiful beautiful I got some
supplies here too we gotta say karma
right I mean I mean let us start so this
prank is actually best viewed from a
time-lapse perspective so we're gonna
see the countdown all over again from
this angle from nine to zero and then it
launches amid a bunch of awesome
fireworks and away it goes
obviously it's a little bit on the slow
side but it's going as fast as it can
and we should pat it on the back and
encourage it anyway so if we speed this
up
it does actually make its way through
the air towards area 7-7 this is when we
all got our flowers out and started
planting them absolutely everywhere and
the bonemeal because of the biomes
didn't actually do that much it just
made more grass so we decided to go with
two block high flowers and plant them
all over the place making this look
really rather pretty
and then the RV hits the cliff and we
had completed the distraction but this
is only part one we're getting close
he's gonna go straight in because cliff
I I don't think this is gonna be
probably the most confusing part for
them just seeing a random RV crashed
into the side of there yes there's also
some very important redstone machines in
these hangars I believe so it's about to
punch down I don't even know crash but I
don't really know what's gonna happen
stop three there we go there come a
little RV you could do it it's done it's
it's there we go it's done there it is
oh it's beautiful I hope they keep that
there forever it's beautiful
we need some flowers up there I think
yeah yeah we got to continue flowering
this place I think we have successfully
flower powered this place I would say so
look at this it's covered it's
ridiculous how many flowers there are I
think bonemeal wasn't even the way to go
it's just these tall flowers that was
the way we still don't need everything
but look at this it's crazy and I mean
we have literally flowered every nook
and cranny of food every block of this
place is flowered to the max it's
beautiful right well I'm sufficiently
busy yeah we can go into the tunnels
should we head over to the tunnels right
now yes I mean we've already got a
couple minutes really they're gonna come
and have a look so we'd better get going
yeah we got to be ready for it we go I
took one for the team All Right see you
later
oh my self come look at this and the
doors open oh yeah no but it looks like
the bamboozle might have work yeah this
is absolutely fine yeah I haven't shown
this on camera but this is the fake
tunnel from the very very start I made a
fake red stone door I made a fake tunnel
with a bit of a bamboozle so if they
came looking for our tunnels this is all
they were gonna find beautiful yes just
to rub salt in the wound that the actual
tunnels have been there we gotta move
even we don't have time to base around
boys come on yeah there's a long tunnel
to run down I just we just got to hope
that the flowers is gonna keep them
interested for long
oh yeah we are in 77 right now but we
just need to make sure if we start
seeing then their names we need to start
crouching okay you know where to go yeah
kind of we need I made this tunnel this
is the correct another one you made goes
to not where the time machine is this
one goes it's quite a long tunnel okay
I'll be honest I didn't quite finish the
tunnel all the way to the end like I got
pretty right and then it just turned
into stone because I just used some tea
I would be pretty deep here man it's
kind of musty that my tunnel goes to the
correct position but Isaac I think no
there's not that great because the
tunnel I think we're way higher than
them I think they're moving about it
looks like they are a little bit oh this
place looks dangerous oh yeah this is
not a good place for holding shift
negative risk well they're still there
they're still down there okay all right
now we're heading away from them
excellent oh no right no no no we didn't
trip a trip wire trap or something did
we that was them right I hope so was
that a Scott sound like I'm still down
there just we need to bide our time so
this is the end of the tunnel I've
already broken through here and this
goes to exactly I call it Crouch I need
to access my inventory who are gonna
risk it well stand in front of you they
won't see ya yeah I don't see any
nametags anymore good oh good yeah I see
his name tied going up and down oh oh oh
he's trying to fly hi
we just got to be patient okay right on
time oh there goes there it goes okay oh
they might have found the flowers now
yeah that's just wait a second oh
they're right on top of us let's just
wait until they go more towards the
other end of area 77 just to be safe if
I tell you if we get caught now the time
machine is gonna get moved and we're
gonna have to go through this whole
thing again yes okay whose names
disappeared
they're definitely joking if they're
flying off God yeah the final okay oh my
goodness great
why the TNC what okay how deep this goes
here we go okay oh it's okay I'm
definitely using TMZ for dramatic effect
okay okay oh my goodness careful I don't
really know where we are hold on let me
get this map this Maps gonna be useless
we're underground which is absolutely
magnificent I do not see them so we're
still good I'm scanning like crazy
there's jelly hey JD hey hi
don't worry about us - and jelly one
they died rip they go in here it's a
house dude there's a house in here let's
try it like what oh my goodness time
but I just looked straight at it
that's it wait what's attached to it why
is there tubes attached to it I just
sorta oh my it's village agreeing wait a
bit it really yes straight-up village
agree and just came out straight out of
that house he's where is it i I'll be
honest
I'll be honest with you I was so
preoccupied beginning the time she and I
completely forgot that they took village
agreein oh my gosh well he looks radiant
in there TNT probably okay yeah like a
mansion complaining I'm kind of jealous
can I get a house like this
please to be honest with the village
agreeance never meticulous add a nice
house to live in he was living in the
tiny little shed at the build-off and
then he was living inside the time
machine this is probably the best place
he's ever lived these guys have been
treating him nice yeah he's put on some
weight like he's been eating healthy
yeah guys I think I'm just gonna leave
him here
I don't really want to try and get him
in the time machine because moving
villages is a pain I think I think he's
cool here he's using the loo right now
anyway we need to get that we need to
get the time machine dude look at it
it's beautiful they done to it as well
they've like linked wiring up to it yeah
turned into a monstrosity I mean do we
even want to turn this thing on I don't
know with the site I've worked too hard
to get this this stupid time machine
back it's definitely some
electromagnetic stuff going on around
here I'm not feeling very good in here I
fire on my arm impulse tanning maybe we
should just leave Green to his toys
barely ready for us in here yeah on this
thing I like kind of busting right now I
have I have a torch is that whole press
the button wait a minute and we turn
three times one
[Music]
brain